Abdul Rehman Majid

Asim Town, Harbanspura, Lahore +923455838361 | abdulrehmanmajid01@gmail.com

Objective

"Highly skilled Frontend Developer with a passion for creating responsive, visually appealing, and user-friendly websites and web applications. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and popular frameworks like React, I specialize in translating design concepts into pixel-perfect, cross-browser compatible interfaces that enhance user experiences and drive engagement."

Experience

• Itsolz 07/2022 - 01/2024

Frontend web Developer

- Delivered front-end development across mobile and web applications.
- Enhanced front-end performance through image optimization and clean coding practices, accelerating load times.
- Created custom websites by harnessing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, SASS, jQuery, JavaScript skills and also work on React Frontend Template.
- Scheduled meetings with clients to discuss website design preference and requirements.
- implement effective user interfaces for client in React.

• Marvis Lab 02/2022 - 06/2022

Frontend developer internee

- Designed and implemented website interface for mobile, desktop and tablets.
- Built reusable code that could be utilized in other projects.
- Demonstrated expertise in HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript Bootstrap.
- Created responsive designs to ensure compatibility across multiple and browsers.
- o Collaborated with designers and back-end developers to implement effective user interfaces

• Abit Consulting 08/2021 - 12/2021

WordPress Developer Internship

- Provided technical support on the usage of WordPress-based websites.
- Implemented WordPress websites from design concepts.
- Used multiple plugin and also implemented wp-form
- Understood functional requirements and adapted design work accordingly.
- Added built-in blogging to enable writing, editing and producing fresh and consistent content on website.

Education

University of Gujarat Bachelor of computer science GPA: 3.07 Punjab college Intermediate in Pre-Eng 69% Al-Falah School

Skills

79%

- Bootstrap
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/jQuery
- React.JS
- · Tailwind CSS

Matriculation

- SASS
- GitHub

- · Microsoft office
- WordPress
- Elementor builder
- · Shopify theme development
- Research
- Website optimization
- Content Management System (CMS)
- Animation
- Project Management
- Pixel Perfect Landing Page DesignFigma/Pxd/Xd to Html

Interest

- Development
- Mobile Games
- · Computer science
- Web Development

Language

- Urdu
- English